Rensselaer County Greens; Records apap192
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:, 1999-2004; 1; 5.33 cubic ft.
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, New York State Department of Environmental Conservation Briefs, 2003-2004 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 30)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, NYSDEC Interim Decision and Responsiveness Summary, 2003 August 22; 2004 March (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 31)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, NYSDEC Reply, 2003 July 11 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 32)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, NYSDEC Permit, 2004 October 3 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 33)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, New York State Department of Public Service Briefs, 2003-2004 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 34)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, NYSDPS Responses, 2003-2004 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 35)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, NYSDPS Appendix B, 2004 April 7 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 36)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, Rensselaer County Greens Briefs, 2003-2004 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 1)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, RCG Cost/Benefit Analysis, 2002 July (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 2)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, RCG Pre-Hearing Intervention Remarks and RCG Statement, 2003 August 13; Undated (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 3)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, RCG Funding, 2002 June-July (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 4)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, Organichem Corporation Application for Full Party Status, 2002 July 5 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 5)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, Approved Permits, 2004 September (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 6)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, Traffic Analysis and Rulings, 2004 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 7)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, Rulings, 2002/2004 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 8)
  - Environmental Concerns, ESNP PM 2, 5 Mobile Source Analysis", 2002 November 15 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 9)
  - Environmental Concerns, Death, Disease & Dirty Power", 2000 October (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 10)
  - Environmental Concerns, Air Pollution Research and Statistics, 2000; 2002; Undated (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 11)
  - Environmental Concerns, Air Pollution Research and Statistics, 2000-2001 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 12)
  - Environmental Concerns, George Bush Cartoons, Undated (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 13)
  - Environmental Concerns, Technology and Paper Articles, 2001; 2003 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 14)
  - Environmental Concerns, Energy and Biofuel Articles, 2000-2002 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 15)
  - Environmental Concerns, Research on Newsprint Industry, 2002-2003 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 16)
  - Environmental Concerns, Research on Newsprint Industry, 2002 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 17)
  - Environmental Concerns, Research on Newsprint Industry, 2000-2001 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 18)
  - Environmental Concerns, Research on Newsprint Industry, Articles on Besicorps history, 1998-2000 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 19)
  - Environmental Concerns, Additional Visual Information (1 of 2), Undated (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 20)
  - Environmental Concerns, Additional Visual Information (2 of 2), Undated (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 21)
  - Environmental Concerns, Additional Visual Information (1 of 2), 2002; Undated (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 22)
  - Environmental Concerns, Additional Visual Information (2 of 2), 2002; Undated (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 23)
  - Environmental Concerns, Technical Conference, 2002 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 24)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Pollutants, Gas Turbine Emissions, Diesel, and Pollution Offsets, 2000 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 25)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Info on Besicorp in the Hudson Valley Prior to Rensselaer County, 1999-2000 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 26)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Ordered Information on Besicorp in the Hudson Valley, 1998-2000 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 27)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, SEQRA, 1999 (Box 4 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 28)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Past Case Examples, 1997; 1999; 2001 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 1)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Impacts on Property Values [BEDCO], 2002 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 2)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Study on Traffic Problems and how to Solve them, 2001-2002 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 3)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Public Involvement Program, 2002 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 4)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Article X/SEQRA Processes, 1998-1999; 2001-2002 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 5)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Empire State Newsprint Project Overview, 2000-2001 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 6)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Local News Clippings on Besicorp, Times Union, 1998-2004 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 7)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Local News Clippings on Besicorp, The Record, 2000-2004 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 8)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Local News Clippings on Besicorp, Rensselaer TU, Independent, Metroland, etc., 1999-2004 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 9)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, RCGs Flyers, Handouts, etc., 2000-2004 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 10)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Besicorps Flyers and Newsletters, 2000-2004 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 11)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Random Information Relating to Besicorp and Rensselaer, 1999-2004 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 12)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Information and Guidelines on how to win a Court Case, 1979; 1981-1982; Undated (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 13)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, DEC Policy System, Permit, and Record of Decision, 2000-2003 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 14)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Visual Resources for US Army Corps of Engineers, 1988 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 15)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Waterfront Planning for Albany, New York, 1996; 2002 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 16)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Urban/Waterfront Planning in Rensselaer, 1986-1987; 1996 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 17)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, City of Rensselaer Planning and Development Agency, 2002 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 18)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, City of Rensselaer Zoning Ordinance, 1979 (Box 5 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 19)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Rensselaer County Industrial Development Agency, 2001 (Box 6 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 1)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Besicorp, Benefit or Burden? Press Release, and IDA, 2002 (Box 6 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 2)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Notices, Replies, Memorandums, 2002-2004 (Box 6 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 3)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Notices, Replies, Memorandums, 2000-2002 (Box 6 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 4)
  - Environmental Research and Background Information, Memorandums, 2003-2004 (Box 6 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 5)
- BASF, 1979-2003; 2; 0.7 cubic ft.
  This series contains information on the history of BASF back to its corporate roots in Germany. The history of the dye industry in Rensselaer traced back to 1868 is also available. This series also includes statistics of the BASF brownfield in Rensselaer, information on BASFs response to RCGs claims, the history of the BASFs landfill, and the land investigation that took place.
  - BASF, History of Company in Germany and United States (IG Farben and GAF), 1988; 1999; 2001-2002 (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 1)
  - BASF, Statistics of Chemicals in Rensselaer, Undated (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 2)
  - BASF, Brownfield Bill/DEC Remediation, 2001-2003; Undated (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 3)
  - BASF, Environmental Releases for Rensselaer County, 2000 (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 4)
  - BASF, Rensselaer Landfill Site History, 1980; 1982; 2001-2002 (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 5)
  - BASF, Work Plans made for BASF, 2001 (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 6)
  - BASF, Feasibility Study Report for BASF, 2001 (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 7)
  - BASF, Petition to BASF Land Reclassification and Land Investigation, 1979-2001 (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 8)
  - BASF, Land Investigation Information, 2002 (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 9)
  - BASF, Land Investigation Information and Maps, 2003 (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 10)
  - BASF, BASF Stocks and Mergers from Morningstar.com, 2000 (Box 1 (2-BASF), Folder 11)
  - BASF, Maps assembled by Rensselaer County Greens Regarding Environmental Remediation needed and BASF Plans, ca. 2000-2003 (Flat-file 1)
- Chip Fab, 1998-2004; 3; 0.6 cubic ft.
  The Chip Fab series compares the positives and negatives of this semiconductor plant. Information on the employment and revenue impacts versus the pollution potential, health hazards, and industry instability is scattered throughout the series. Other semiconductor manufacturers in New York and their statistics are available here as well. Health hazards such as high employee cancer risks, and water pollution and usage cause microchip plants to be dangerous. A geometrical report and a water supply study are each located in folders in the series. Local news clippings show how the community rallied against the Chip Fab project and prevented it from being constructed despite the influence of politicians who wanted the company to be built in North Greenbush.
  - Chip Fab, Traffic Impact Study, 1998 November (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 1)
  - Chip Fab, Traffic Impact Study, 1998 November (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 2)
  - Chip Fab, Input on Environmental Health and Safety Impacts, and Semiconductor Industry Strategy, Undated (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 3)
  - Chip Fab, High-tech Centers in the Capital District, 1999-2001 (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 4)
  - Chip Fab, Local News Clippings, Times Union, 1999-2004 (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 5)
  - Chip Fab, Local News Clippings, The Record, The Advertiser, etc., 1998-2000 (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 6)
  - Chip Fab, Transcripts and Statements against Chip Fab, 1999 (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 7)
  - Chip Fab, Presentation and Information as to why North Greenbush should not accept Chip Fab, 1999 (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 8)
  - Chip Fab, Other Semiconductors in New York and their Hazards, 1999 (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 9)
  - Chip Fab, Geometrical Report for Chip Fab, 1998 August 19 (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 10)
  - Chip Fab, Archeological Field Investigations, 1998 (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 11)
  - Chip Fab, Water Supply Study, 1998 (Box 1 (3-Chip Fab), Folder 12)
- Other Projects, 2000-2004; 4; 0.33 cubic ft.
  This series contains information about other projects undertaken by the Rensselaer County Greens (RCG). A proposed I-90 connector in the town of North Greenbush was opposed by the Rensselaer County Greens and community opposition to the proposed project was organized. (They believed it was unnecessary and was not worth the destruction of woodlands and the sprawl that would result.) Other information on urban sprawl shows how proposed tax legislation would cause surrounding farmland and country to be quickly inhabited.
  In 1913, Freihofer purchased a building constructed in 1896 in Lansingburgh, NY. The Freihofer building became a community fixture. In 2000, the drugstore chain Eckerds planned on demolishing the building to replace it with one of its box design store fronts. The RCG intervened, and eventually the building was saved from demolition. The news clippings and handouts in the series depict this. It remains a historic site on the Hudson River.
  In 2002, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute began spending a quarter of a billion dollars on new buildings on its campus, becoming known as the RPI Expansion Project. The project became a sore spot for the RCG. Six houses built in the 1800s that were still structurally sound were to be destroyed to make room for the construction. RCG believed the area would also suffer aesthetically and traffic would become a bigger issue. This RCG project is documented in a report by the RCG in the series.
  A Report to the Community located in the toxic spraying folder explains the RCGs opposition to spraying chemicals of unknown health risks in the community to prevent West Nile Virus. The question of whether the chemicals or virus posed more of a threat was an issue. News clippings and RCG handouts depict the efforts many of the members of the Troy community were willing to go to to prevent potentially harmful chemicals from being randomly sprayed throughout the city.
  - I-90 Connector and Sprawl, 2000-2002 (Box 1 (4-Other Projects), Folder 1)
  - Freihofers, Exhibits and News Clippings, 2000-2004 (Box 1 (4-Other Projects), Folder 2)
  - RPI Expansion Project, 2000-2002 (Box 1 (4-Other Projects), Folder 3)
  - Toxic Spraying, Report to the Community, 2000 September (Box 1 (4-Other Projects), Folder 4)
  - Toxic Spraying, Community Uprising, 2000 (Box 1 (4-Other Projects), Folder 5)
- Audiovisuals, 1999-2003; 5; 11 videocassettes; 32
  The moving images in this series are visual documentation of the projects and issues of interest to the Rensselaer County Greens. The series includes commercial and non-commercial films documenting public hearings dealing with Besicorp and community meetings dealing with Troys waterfront. The VHS about BASF titled Locked Out! is based on the companys so-called attack on workers and the environment at their company located in Louisiana.
  - BASF, DEC Hearing, 2003 March 4 (Video-tape 1)
  - BASF, Locked Out! The Story of BASFs Attack on Workers, the Community, and the Environment in Louisiana", Undated (Video-tape 2)
  - Besicorp, Public Hearing, 2002 September 10 (Video-tape 3)
  - Besicorp, DEC/DPS Public Hearing, 2001 January 30 (Video-tape 4)
  - Besicorp, Public Hearing, Air and Water Issues, 2001 March 14 (Video-tape 5)
  - Besicorp, Public Hearing, "Community Impacts", 2001 March 29 (Video-tape 6)
  - Besicorp, Public Hearing, "Safety/Material Use", 2001 April 3 (Video-tape 7)
  - Besicorp, Public Hearing, Final Scoping Sesion, 2001 May 24 (Video-tape 8)
  - Besicorp, Scoping Session, 2001 February 6 (Video-tape 9)
  - North Greenbush/Defreestville Town Board Meeting, 2000 December 14 (Video-tape 10)
  - Rensselaer City Council Meeting, 2000 (Video-tape 11)
  - Rezoning R. 4/43, North Greenbush Town Meeting, 2000 December 14 (Video-tape 12)
  - South Troy Waterfront, Community Meeting, 2000 November 9 (Video-tape 13)
  - Troy Planning Commission, The Drugstore Wars", 2001 Fall (Video-tape 14)
  - BASF, DEC Hearing, 2003 March 4 (Cassette 1)
  - Besicorp, DEC/DPS Public Hearing, 2001 January 30 (Cassette 2)
  - Besicorp, Council Meeting, 2002 June 10 (Cassette 3)
  - Besicorp, Public Hearing, 2000 November-December (Cassette 4)
  - Besicorp, Public Hearing, "Air and Water Issues", 2001 March 14 (Cassette 5)
  - Besicorp, Public Hearing, "Community Impacts", 2001 March 29 (Cassette 6)
  - Besicorp, Public Hearing, "Safety/Material Use", 2001 April 3 (Cassette 7)
  - Besicorp, Public Hearing, Final Scoping Sesion, 2001 May 24 (Cassette 8)
  - Besicorp, Rensselaer City Council Meeting, 2002 June 7 (Cassette 9)
  - Besicorp, Rensselaer City Council Meeting, 2000 November 9 (Cassette 10)
  - Besicorp, Rensselaer County Environmental Management Council, Undated (Cassette 11)
  - Besicorp, Scoping Session, Undated (Cassette 12)
  - Chip Fab, Community Forum, 1999 April 28 (Cassette 13)
  - Chip Fab, North Greenbush Town Meeting, 1999 (Cassette 14)
  - Chip Fab, Master Plan Committee, Report on Chip Fab, Workshop Meeting, 1999 September 23 (Cassette 15)